Brad Blackburn

Creative Director | UX/UI | Animator

Eagle, ID - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Brad-Blackburn/387d0451afdab400

ARTIST BIO:

Brad Blackburn is an accomplished visual artist providing skilled leadership and professional expertise in the creative services industry. With a career spanning nearly 20 years, Brad has worked as a professional in the creative services industry, leading various creative teams and supporting a diverse range of clientele. His skills cover a wide gamut of the arts, and he has worked on projects ranging from commercial branding, UI/UX for web & mobile products, and production design on Fortune 500 company commercial shoots.

Early on, Brad was trained as a fine artist throughout his primary education, and went on to earn his first degree from Edison College in fine art in 2000. Afterward he attended Liberty University where he received a bachelors degree in Communication in 2005 and bachelors in Religion in 2007. "When I was in college, I was encouraged to have a personal maxim. After much consideration I finally came to mine and it rings true for me both personally and professionally - 'Proclaim and restore Goodness, Beauty and Truth to and in others around you'. This maxim has served me well as an artist, reminding me of my mission and giving focus to my work."

Brad continues using his artistic abilities to help clients reach their goals through engaging media experiences. His background in fine arts and leadership training affords him and his clients a professional perspective not found among most designers in the market today.

Specialties:

Creative Leadership

Brand Design

User Interface / Experience (UI / UX) Design - for web, mobile, print, graphics

Photography

Magazine / Direct Mail / Print Advertising design

Motion Graphics

Animation - 2D/3D

Film and video Production Design

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Creative Director

Churchill Strategies - Harrisburg, PA - February 2017 to Present

As the Creative Director, I work directly with key organization leadership to influence our company's direction, the kind of clients we work with, as well as supervise all of the creative media output for both internal company media and external client projects. Some of my accomplishments include: Implementing a DAM (Digital Asset Management) system, overhauling the creative workflow process, migrating the company over to an improved PM (Project Management) Tool, Consolidating company brand standards, instituting many other production policies and operating procedures. My duties include: Overseeing the creative team, daily communicating with the Client Managers about project progress and expectations, setting design standards and vision for projects, animating key motion graphics projects, oversee the maintenance and production of all client websites, etc.

Art Director

Shell Point Retirement Community - Fort Myers, FL - August 2014 to September 2016

I was responsible for the overall art direction and visual messaging in print communications published by Shell Point. This included a variety of ongoing monthly advertising campaigns, a monthly 40+ page lifestyle magazine, numerous brochures and newsletters, directing photo shoots, covering events with photography, and working with various outside vendors for printing and photographic support. Additionally I supported online and video advertising by establishing brand standards and creating graphic collateral. My duties also included maintaining a network of 10 Mac computers and working with IT to implement various Active Directory protocols, backup procedures and so forth. I oversaw two graphic designers as part of my team and reported to the director of marketing.

During my tenure I was able to implement several graphic policies and establish, procedures including: Asset management organization, photography protocols, brand standards, project management procedures, etc. I was directly responsible for implementing a project management system into our production workflow. Similarly, I also implemented a DAM for the photo and project catalogue, consisting of 4+ terabytes of data.

Creative Director

B2B Studios LLC - Fort Myers, FL - June 2007 to 2015

B2B Studios is a full-service digital arts agency offering creative design services to clients all over the country.

As the creative director my duties were many and various. They range from business development, client acquisition / relationship, creative direction, primary designer / artist and so on. I have worked on such projects as commercial film production,

production design, interactive digital print, SAAS UI/UX design, mobile UI/UX design, flash based RIA's, national and regional branding campaigns, motion graphics, 3D animation, 2D animation, web design/development, social marketing campaigns and creative consulting. A list of notable clients includes GE, Harley Davidson, Cisco, Avaya, AEP, Convio, WCI, Jamie Foxx, Rashad Jennings (NFL running back), Southern Baptist Convention, Texas A&M university, Liberty University, Etc.

Digital Supervisor

Liberty University - Lynchburg, VA - October 2005 to June 2007

Was responsible for the supervision and creative development of all major web endeavors put forth by the university and affiliated organizations. This included the production of engaging websites, online marketing campaigns, and interactive environments/presentations. As such, I personally managed a creative development team of 11 persons, and coordinated projects with IT Dev, Marketing, and many other departments. My position required that I report on a daily basis directly to the university C.I.O. and weekly to the university President/Chancellor and Executive Vice President. Personally instituted and supervised the graphic development of over 15 unique websites for the university. Was responsible for developing a total 3D interactive environment of the university's facilities, encompassing more than 3 million sq. ft. of facility space situated on a 4,400-acre campus. Independently assessed by three outside consulting firms, the minimum production value of this project was estimated to be worth a minimum of 2.3 million dollars. This project required the 3D modeling and animation of all campus facilities, the development of an engaging user interface design (GUI), video and presentation elements using green screen methods, interactive min-game development, scriptwriting and copy content editing, etc. Managed the online SEO / SEM , Ad / Lead generation for all university websites and landing pages. Created online marketing campaigns in tandem with the Director of Marketing.

Graphic Artist

4What Interactive - Naples, FL - June 2003 to June 2006

Created the following: Website compositions, promotional and marketing materials, Kiosk presentations, IP Phone Training programs, website build outs etc. Working mainly using flash/actionscript, photoshop, html/css. Clients include: Discover, Citrix, Cisco Systems, Marsh, The Hartford, WCI and other national property developers.

EDUCATION

B.S. in Graphic Design

LIBERTY UNIVERSITY

SKILLS

Design, Leadership, Web, 3D, Animation, Video, Photography, Print production, Mobile, Branding, UI/UX, Motion Graphics (10+ years)

LINKS

http://behance.net/iambradblackburn

http://linkedin.com/in/bradblackburn

http://www.iambradblackburn.com

http://www.krop.com/b2bstudios

http://www.vimeo.com/b2bstudios

PUBLICATIONS

Shell Point Life

http://www.shellpoint.net/shellpointlife/

I have been the Art director of the magazine since August 2014, and am responsible for the graphic and visual look of each edition. I directly create each cover and either work with a photographer or shoot each of the feature photography myself. I supervise 2 graphic designers who work with me to produce each issue.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

--SKILLSET--

LEADERSHIP • Account/Project Management, Team leadership, Client Acquisition, Business Strategy, Creative Direction

DESIGN • Adobe Suite, Advertising Collateral, Wireframing/Prototyping, UI/UX, Branding/Logo Identity

WEB • XHTML, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Flash, XML/PHP for Flash, WordPress

3D • Cinema 4D, Google Sketchup, Architectural Modeling, Lighting and Rendering

ANIMATION / VIDEO • After Effects, Premiere Pro, Final Cut Studio, Cinema 4D, Cinemaphotography, Production Design

MOBILE • iOS App Design/Branding

--KEY EXPERIENCE--

10+ Years Design

10+ Years 3D and animation

10+ Years Web design & development

10+ Years Agency experience

10+ Years Creative leadership

10+ Years Branding

06 Years Print

04 Years Film / Production Design